Guide to the Frederick William Buchholz Papers 1863-1929
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Frederick William Buchholz Papers
1863-1929
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA, 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 204
Buchholz, Frederick William
1 linear foot of shelf space 2 boxes
Correspondence of F. W. Buchholz, texts of sermons, and clippings and photographs. In addition there are correspondence, diaries, certificates and other papers of Helena Frances Richter Spalding Buchholz and her step-daughter Effie L. Spalding.
Frederick William Buchholz (1841-1929) was a German Methodist minister in Eastern Washington, circa 1886-1907.
This collection contains correspondence of F. W. Buchholz concerning church politics, business activities, primarily as officer of the Yellow Jacket Gold Mining Company, Spokane, Washington, and family matters concerning litigation over lands and estates; also texts of sermons, circa 1871-1893, and clippings and photographs concerning the German Methodist Church in Washington State. In addition there are correspondence, diaries, certificates and other papers of Helena Frances Richter Spalding Buchholz and her stepdaughter Effie L. Spalding concerning social, educational and literary activities in Chicago and Waukegan, Illinois.
This collection is arranged in a single series.
This collection is open and available for research use.
This collection was donated to the WSU Libraries by Helena Frances Richter Spalding Buchholz.
Buchholz, Frederick William; Buchholz, Helena Frances Richter Spalding; Spalding, Effie L.
Chicago (Ill.) -- Social life and customs; Methodists -- Washington (State) -- Correspondence; Mineral industries -- Washington (State) -- Spokane; Mineral industries -- Finance -- Washington (State) -- Spokane; Yellow Jacket Gold Mining Company (Spokane, Wash.); Germans -- Washington (State) -- Correspondence
Businesses and Corporations; Elementary and Secondary Education; German Americans; Laws and Legislation; Religion; Washington (State); Spokane; Mines and Mineral Resources
- Correspondence and certificates, 1863-1899 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence and records, 1900-1906 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence and records, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence and records, 1908-1909 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence and records, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Effie L. Spalding diary, 1878-1879 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1912-1913 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1914-1929 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Sermons, 1871-1893 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
- Sweet Clover Literary Club (Chicago), 1896-1897 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Clippings, photographs and miscellaneous items, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Supporting documentation for collection (genealogy) (Box 2, Folder 8)